你愿意的话可以坐下
Sit down if you want to.
我不知我会遇到谁
I didn't know who I might meet
或他们会问我什么
or what they might ask.
你有没有乘过真正的捕虾船？
You ever been on a real shrimp boat?
没有
No.
可我乘过一条真正的大捕虾船
But I been on a real big boat.
我指的是一种专门捕虾的船
I'm talking about a shrimp catching boat.
我一直都在捕虾船上干活
I been working on shrimp boats all my life .
开始是我叔叔的船
I started out on my uncle's boat
那时我大概9岁
when I was about maybe 9.
我刚在考虑自己去买一条船
I was just looking into buying my own boat
然后就应征入伍了
and got drafted.
我的名字叫本杰明巴弗布鲁
My given name is Benjamin Buford Blue.
人们都管我叫布巴
People call me Bubba,
好像个乡下佬的名字
just like one of them old red neck boys.
很难以置信吧？
Can you believe that?
我叫福雷斯甘
My name's Forrest Gump.
人们都管我叫福雷斯甘
People call me Forrest Gump.
布巴来自亚拉巴州拉巴特湾
So Bubba was from Bayou La Batre, Alabama,
他的妈妈是煮虾的
and his mama cooked shrimp.
她的妈妈也是煮虾的
And her mama before her cooked shrimp,
还有她妈妈的妈妈也是煮虾的
and her mama before her mama cooked shrimp, too.
布巴家的人了解所有
Bubba's family knew everything
跟捕虾有关的事情
there was to know about the shrimping business.
我知道所有
I know everything there is to know
跟捕虾有关的事情
about the shrimping business.
我自己也准备去捕虾
I'm going into the shrimping business for myself
等我退伍之后
after I get out of the army.